William T. Dafeldecker

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Dedicated IT professional with the ability to adapt, excel and master new environments and technologies in a quick time frame. Exceptional written and verbal communication skills in-person and online providing customer support, talking to management about a technical issue and resolution, or communications through electronic format. Honorable discharge serving six years of exceptional military service showing I am disciplined, and reliable as demonstrated exceptional military service resulting in effective leadership and team oriented problem solving.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

New Jersey Judiciary- Trenton, NJ Information Technology Analyst 3

11/2015-Present

Day/Night Phone: 732-551-7359 Cell williamdafeldecker@gmail.com

- As Website Project Leader I constantly go through and look for ways to improve www.njcourts.gov and the Judiciary's
 - internal website (Infonet). Responsibilities and duties include, but are not limited to:
 - Various projects that range from web page improvements to creating new solutions to improve workplace/website efficiency.
 - Project planning when we need to come up with a solution to an issue or a request.
 - Constantly communicating with various team leadership throughout the Judiciary to establish a resolution to their needs.
 - ° Oversee design and front-end development and software for its internal and external websites.
 - Extensive knowledge of enterprise-level content management systems, SharePoint (2013, 2016, O365), Drupal, server and client-side scripting, PHP, HTML 5, CSS3, and JavaScript. Familiarity with TypeScript, AngularJS, React, Java, Linux, MySQL, SQL, SOAP, REST, TCP/IP, TLS and IIS.
 - Oversee management of the hardware infrastructure and back-end setup for its internal and external websites.
 - Developed a solution for a Statewide Municipal Court Closing system to will allow the public to view local municipal court
 closings when applicable. We utilize a service to call custom Python script, that is bundled into an executable on a
 Windows 2012 server to query data in Sharepoint. If there were any changes, it would then write out the closing
 information to the webserver.
 - Project lead on moving the Judiciary's internal website (Infonet) off of IBM's WCM and onto a temporary IIS Server to sanitize and prepare data for our next Content Management System. Project involved configuring IIS server, querying data out of WCM, and designing a new site layout for the Infonet.
 - Assisted in deploying an enterprise level Elastic Search on a RHEL server that utilized Apache Tomcat. The solution used a custom web crawler to consume, index, and assign search facets for a better user experience.
 - Project lead on the Judiciary's website's new design and construction that receives over 26 million views a year. With the
 redesign, I have implemented current technology such as, but not limited to, site responsiveness through Bootstrap, HTML5,
 dynamic pages, new JavaScript libraries, and storing/presenting data through JSON, XML, AJAX, and various functionality
 to increase the site's Search Engine Optimization, accessibility, and findability.
 - Identified a problem with the way secure areas were being handled and, by coordinating with other IT departments, we came up with a solution to provide a reliable environment for the committee members to share information via WebSeal. This solution integrates with the existing Active Directory to allow users to sign in with ease.
 - Project lead on creating and implementing a new Jury Reporting Message system used by over 120 personnel all throughout
 the state of New Jersey. I conducted numerous meetings, provided presentations, and wrote up instructional documents for
 various Judiciary teams to coordinate a new and efficient way for Jury Managers to provide urgent information to Jurors. I
 created a python script that I bundled into an executable and installed as a service on a Windows 2012 server to automate
 the process of moving over messages created by users into a production environment.
 - Configured and maintained LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, and PHP) stack environment on a Red Hat Enterprise Linux server to support a development area for Drupal CMS.
 - Provide customer support to various content providers through email, instant messaging, and phone calls throughout the Judiciary to provide precise and current information to the public as well as employees.
 - Utilize IBM WCM for Infonet updates. Proven resourceful in self-learning a deeper understanding of the product in order to update content, troubleshoot issues, and improve areas where appropriate.
 - Troubleshoot and resolve complex issues, along with Judiciary Information Technology Teams that I have built a rapport, to solve issues outside the scope of my unit.
 - Mentor other team members by providing professional and technical assistance when needed to provide a knowledge transfer
 and unit growth. Have gone through and created (or verified) Web Teams full library of How To instructions on Web Team
 responsibilities.
 - Proven resourceful in instances where newer technologies/methodologies are used to enhance the website experience and workplace effectiveness
 - Self-taught Bootstrap toolkit to use with new website design and to teach team.
 - Used Python to create custom plugins to make day-to-day work be done more effective and efficiently.
 - Developed multiple scripts in Python, bundled into an executable, and set up as services on a Windows server to automate daily processes increasing team efficiency and effectiveness.
 - Learned web site accessibility standards put forth by the Americans with Disabilities Act.

Researched Apache configuration settings to address issues and new requests to enhance website.

Ocean County Government - Toms River, NJ

12/2014-11/2015

Communications Technician

- Maintain countywide radio network for Ocean County public service departments. Had to respond to outages/off-hour downtime when necessary to support Emergency Services.
- Efficiently program different code plugs into various Motorola radio models for multiple county divisions.
- Maintain Ocean County radio network via virtual machines and manually apply various Windows and Motorola patches monthly.

Offerit - Morganville, NJ 7/2012- 03/2015

Tier One Programmer/Support

- Provide remote client software support through email or instant messaging for various web-based programs using Linux based web servers. Support is also provided remotely via SSH access onto servers as well as accessing client's software remotely. Would access the servers mainly through Putty.
- Would create/utilize shell scripting to automate processes for software installation. Would have to adapt scripts to individual client's servers to ensure proper installation. Developing the scripts would require an analysis of existing data, and often times cleaning up the data, in preparation for bulk imports.
- Mostly in PHP/Smarty, would develop new software features as requested by clients. Would also go through and create solutions to code-based bugs.
- Assist clients in setting up MySQL databases and installing data tables for software use. Correct and manage client's MySQL databases through the CLI or PHP scripting.
- Would often work with hosting companies to resolve server side issues affecting software.
- Would set up server backups for clients via custom shell scripts and utilizing server cron.
- Would assist clients in tracking their traffic to certain servers/sites/pages upon request.

US Navy 7/2005-7/2011

Electronics Technician Second Class

- Supervisor for Combat Electronics work center, managing personnel while troubleshooting and performing maintenance and repairs to vital electronics.
- NMCI Network Coordinator who created/managed computer network accounts for all personnel through Active Directory
- Electronic Support Supervisor, involved knowledgeable management of individual division during normal operations and fast reaction for self and watch team to casualty control procedures during emergency conditions.
- Administered the ship's operating systems through various software/security patches.

QUALIFICATIONS AND TECHNOLOGY EXPERIENCE

- Government Top Secret/Secret security clearance.
- Operating Systems: Managed Windows Desktop Class Operating Systems and Microsoft Office Suite, as well as re-imaging Windows Operating Systems. Experienced in Microsoft SharePoint, and TFS environments.
- Proficient in Linux/Unix based Operating Systems for desktops and servers. Extensive experience using CLI commands.
- Proficient in PHP/Python/Perl/R/C/C#/Java/Javascript/Smarty/HTML5/XML/CSS3/JSON programming languages.
- Proficient in data management via SQL and Microsoft Access.
- Proficient in Linux web server management through Apache and other Linux packages.
- Experienced in Sharepoint 2013, Sharepoint 2016, IBM Web Content Manager, and Drupal environments.
- Work Center Supervisor Responsible for completing all preventative correct maintenance, as well as supervising personnel within work center.
- Proven ability to respond immediately and confidently in emergencies with in-rate Naval Training, Combat Systems Officer
 of the Watch, Damage Control Qualifications, and Force Protection Qualifications.

EDUCATION

United States Navy

- Electronics Technician Apprentice Technical Training. AC Circuits, Basic Digital Circuits, DC Circuits, Solid State Devices.
 Electronics Technician A School
- Communications Systems Operation and Maintenance, High Frequency Transmitters/Receivers, Radar Systems Operation and Maintenance, Technical Orientation. High Frequency/Ultra High/Super High Frequency Systems Maintenance
- Electronics Systems Troubleshooting and Repair, Electronics Laboratory
- Electronics Technician Second Class (Surface)
- Digital Circuits, Electric Circuits, Electronic Circuits, Electronics Systems Troubleshooting and Repair, Electronic
 Laboratory Test Equipment, Microcomputer Applications Software, Microprocessors, Navigation Equipment, Personnel
 Supervision, Technical Mathematics.

Thomas Edison University – B.S. in Information Technology

• Graduated December 2017 with a Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology.